President Truman will be here tomorrow, so all you folks in Dallas turn out.
El presidente Truman llega mañana, así que arreglaos en Dallas.
This is Cowboy Rhythms on KTRN, Wichita Falls.
Ritmos Country en la K TRN, Wichita Falls.
Here's Hank Williams' big hit tune, "Cold, Cold Heart."
Hank Williams, con “Com, Com Heart“.
You ain't ever gonna amount to nothing.
Nunca llegarás a ser nada.
Already spent a dime this morning, ain't even had a decent breakfast.
Ya te has gastado diez centavos, y aún no has desayunado.
Give me the chalk.
Dame la tiza.
Why don't you comb your hair, Sonny?
¿Por qué no te peinas, Sonny? Llevas el pelo de punta.
I'm surprised you had the nerve to show up...
Me sorprende que hayas salido...
...after that stomping you all took last night.
...después de cómo os dieron ayer.
- Well, could've been worse. - What'd you say?
- Pudo ser peor. - ¿Qué dices?
- Could've been worse. - Yeah.
- Sí.
You can say that about nearly everything, I guess.
Eso se puede decir de casi todo.
A few football teams have had some luck with tackling.
Hay equipos con suerte con el placaje.
Keeps the other team from scoring quite so often.
Los contrarios no marcan tanto.
Sounds too rough for me.
Demasiado duro para mí.
You don't even care if it was your last game.
Te da igual tu último partido.
You ain't ever gonna get stomped for your own high-school ball team again.
Nunca volverán a darte por el equipo del instituto.
- Where's your school spirit? - Don't know.
- ¿Y tu espíritu deportivo? - No sé.
You working today?
¿Trabajas hoy?
The truck's being greased.
Están engrasando el camión.
So, you see, this is what I get for betting on my own hometown ball team.
Esto me ocurre por apostar por el equipo de mi pueblo.
I ought to have better sense.
Debí haber tenido más cabeza.
Wouldn't hurt if you had a better hometown.
Te daría igual si tuvierais mejor pueblo.
You mind pointing that at the floor till I get by?
¿Te importa apuntar al suelo?
I don't want my eye poked out.
No quiero quedarme tuerto.
Don't let Billy get too far away, will you, son?
No dejes que Billy se aleje mucho.
You're damn more dangerous in a pool hall than you are on a football field.
Joder, eres más peligroso en un billar que en el campo de fútbol.
Hey-
Sí.
You ever heard of tackling?
¿Sabes qué es placar?
Hey, Duane!
¡Eh, Duane!
Boy, I froze my ass last night!
Tío, anoche me congelé el culo.
Hey, why the hell can't you kids learn to tackle?
¿Nunca aprenderéis a placar?
Hey, how about taking Genevieve some change, being as you're going that way?
Ya que vais para allá, llevadle cambio a Genevieve.
Toss me one!
¡Pásamela!
Pick up the ball, Crawford.
Coge la pelota, Crawford.
Look, Larry, they can catch.
Larry, saben recibir.
Feisty sons of bitches, aren't they? Wish they could tackle.
Qué hijos de puta. Ojalá supieran placar.
Or do something useful.
O hacer algo útil.
Team wasn't worth a kiss-my-ass this year.
El equipo de este año no vale una mierda.
Fade out, Crawford. One more time.
Piérdete, Crawford. Otra vez.
All right, you boys. Cut it out.
Vale, chicos. Dejadlo ya.
I got enough problems without you playing that game over again.
Ya tengo problemas sin que vengáis a jugar.
We could've run off to Mexico with this, you know.
Había suficiente para irnos a México.
- Hey, play the new one we heard. - Which one?
- Pon esa nueva que oímos. - ¿Cuál?
Down payment on breakfast.
Para el desayuno.
Let somebody prosperous play the jukebox.
Que los ricos pongan las canciones.
Nobody prosperous would eat here.
Aquí no vendría ningún rico.
- Well, I ain't very hungry. - Well, I am.
- No tengo hambre. - Pues yo sí.
You want the pickup first tonight?
- ¿Usas la camioneta esta noche? - No.
I oughtn't get it first every Saturday. It's half yours.
No me toca a mí. Es de los dos.
- Go ahead. - You sure?
- Venga. - ¿Seguro?
Sure, I'm sure. Anyways, I got lots of deliveries to make.
Seguro. Además, tengo un montón de entregas.
- And I have to go clear to Ranger. - Okay.
- Y tengo que hablar con Ranger. - Vale.
I'll be lucky to get back for the second show.
Con suerte llegaré a la segunda sesión.
My goodness, Sonny.
Dios mío, Sonny.
Frank oughtn't work you so late on weekends.
Trabajas demasiado el fin de semana.
That's what I keep telling him.
Eso digo yo.
You ain't got in in time to see the comedy in three weeks.
Hace tres semanas que llegas tarde a la película.
Hope you don't want popcorn, because there ain't none.
Espero que no quieras palomitas, no quedan.
And you missed the newsreel too.
Y te has perdido las noticias.
The main show's done started, so I'll just charge you 30 cents.
La sesión ya ha empezado, solo te cobro 30 centavos.
Thanks, Miss Mosey.
Gracias.
I was wondering if my daughter had deserted us too, when I heard her voice.
Me preguntaba si mi hija se había ido, cuando oí su voz.
Pa! Pa! Hi, Pa.
¡Papá! Hola, papá,
Kay was our only daughter.
Kay era nuestra hija.
I know a father's not supposed to have favourites, but when it's Kay...
Un padre no debería tener favoritos, pero si era Kay...
- You smell good. - You like it?
- Hueles bien. - ¿Te gusta?
- What's that? - An atomiser.
- ¿Qué es? - Perfume.
What'd you get? A present?
¿Es un regalo?
Who from?
¿De quién?
Somebody.
De una persona.
I decided you had a wreck.
Creía que habías tenido un accidente.
What's happened to you? You look different.
¿Qué ha ocurrido? Te veo distinta.
- I do? - Yeah.
¿En serio?
You look all lit up inside.
Pareces brillar por dentro.
You're not wearing your usual deadpan look.
No tienes tu expresión normal.
That "How'd I ever get into this family?" look.
La de «¿Qué hago yo en esta familia?”.
Father.
Padre.
You've been taking those vitamins Dr Gray sent you.
Te has tomado las vitaminas del doctor Gray.
That's right.
Será eso.
I guess I'll get me some of those vitamins.
Creo que yo también me las tomaré.
I'll get it, Delilah.
Ya voy yo, Delilah.
What's the matter with her? She looks kind of queer.
¿Qué sucede? Parece como mareada.
- Guess what. - What?
- ¿Sabes una cosa? - ¿Qué?
- It's our anniversary.
- Es nuestro aniversario.
We've been going steady a year tonight.
Hoy hace un año que salimos juntos.
Yeah?
¿Sí?
Seems like a lot longer.
Pues parece mucho más.
You should've got me some anniversary present.
Debías traerme un regalo de aniversario.
You can have another stick of gum. That's all I got on me.
Te puedo dar otro chicle. No tengo nada más.
You can give me a dollar too.
Dame un dólar.
That's how much it cost me and Marlene for the show.
Es lo que nos costó entrar a Marlene y a mí.
Hi. What are y'all doing back here in the dark?
¿Qué hacéis a oscuras aquí detrás?
- He's coming for me in a few minutes. - I'll get your coffee.
- Vendrá a buscarme enseguida. - Te traeré un café.
- Where'd the boys go? - Ben had some date.
- ¿Y los chicos? - Ben tenía una cita.
Tommy went for basketball practice.
Tommy ha ido a entrenar.
I don't see why they should get the pickup first all the time.
No sé por qué siempre tienen ellos la camioneta primero.
All they ever wanna do is neck anyway.
Lo único que quieren es besuquearse.
Buckley says that's not too young for them to marry.
Buckley dice que no son muy jóvenes para casarse.
- I didn't marry your mother till I was 25. - Oh, I know, Pop.
- No me casé con tu madre hasta los 25. - Lo sé, papá.
- Need some help, Jessie? - Yeah, sure do.
- ¿Te ayudo, Jesse'? - Si, por favor.
- So long, Sam. - Bye, Sam.
- Hasta luego, Sam. - Adiós.
- Come on. - Good night.
- Vamos. - Buenas noches.
- Good night. Sure did like the picture. - Well, good.
- Me ha gustado la película. - Me alegro.
- Good night.
- Buenas noches.
Crack your window. Leave the motor running.
Sube la ventana y no apagues el motor.
It's just too cold in here.
Hace un frío que pela.
Your hands are like ice!
¡Tienes las manos heladas!
Put on my gloves.
Me pondré guantes.
What's the matter with you? You act plain bored.
¿Pero qué te ocurre? No me haces caso.
Quit! Quit!
¡Quita!
You said this was our anniversary.
¿No es nuestro aniversario?
Let's do something different.
Hagamos algo diferente.
Well, I like that! You cheapskate.
Bueno, ¿cómo qué, tacaño?
Didn't even get me a present, and now you wanna get me pregnant.
No me compras nada, y ahora quieres dejarme embarazada.
My God, Charlene! It was just my hand.
Por Dios, Charlene. Solo era mi mano.
Yeah. One thing leads to another.
Ya. Una cosa lleva a la otra.
My mama told me how that old stuff goes.
Mi madre ya me ha contado cómo va eso.
We'll have plenty of time for that when we get married.
Tendremos tiempo de sobra cuando estemos casados.
You wasn't no livelier than me.
Estabas tan animada como yo.
Because you ain't good-looking enough. You ain't even got a ducktail.
Porque no eres lo bastante guapo. Y además no te peinas.
Well, anyway, I'm done late.
De todas formas, llego tarde.
Let's go on home.
Vamos a casa.
Some anniversary.
Algún otro aniversario.
If that's the way you feel about it, I'd just as soon break up, Charlene.
Si eso es lo que piensas, casi prefiero romper.
I don't wanna spoil no more anniversaries for you.
No quiero estropearte ningún aniversario más.
That's the way nice girls get treated in this town!
¡Aquí tratan así a las buenas chicas!
I might've known you wasn't dependable.
No tendría que haberme fiado de ti.
You wasn't even in the backfield either.
Ni fuiste a jugar el partido.
This jacket's got a hole in the pocket, but don't ask me to sew it for you.
Esta chaqueta está agujereada, pero no pienso cosértela.
You can give me back my pictures too.
Y devuélveme mis fotos.
I don't want you showing all the other boys and telling how hot I am.
No quiero que las enseñes y les cuentes lo buena que estoy.
You wasn't very hot.
No estás tan buena.
I hope you ain't down in the mouth about Charlene.
No estarás deprimido por Charlene.
- I ain't blue about her. - What are you blue about then?
- No estoy triste por ella. - ¿Y por qué estás triste?
Ain't nobody to go with in this town.
Aquí no hay nadie con quien salir.
Jacy's the only pretty girl in school and Duane's got her.
Jacy es la única chica guapa y sale con Duane.
I'd call that his tough luck.
Eso es mala suerte.
You don't have to eat so fast. You ain't in a race.
No comas tan rápido. No es una carrera.
Jacy will bring you more misery than she'll ever be worth.
Jacy solo te traerá desgracias.
Did your dad give you this?
¿Te lo ha dado tu padre?
He needs all he's got.
No le sobra el dinero.
Wouldn't hurt you to take something from him once in a while.
No te haría mal cogerle algo de vez en cuando.
I don't know. You and Duane both in a boarding house.
No sé. Tú y Duane en una pensión.
Him with the mother, and you with the father. Don't seem right.
Él tiene madre y tú, padre. No me parece bien.
And your dad's taking too many pills, you know.
Tu padre toma demasiadas pastillas, ¿sabes?
Yeah.
Sí.
But I'm no one to talk.
Pero no debería hablar.
I never did get on with Mama. I still don't.
Nunca me he llevado bien con mi madre.
Say, I hear Dan's going back to work soon.
He oído que Dan volverá a trabajar.
- I guess you'll be quitting before long. - Honey...
- Supongo que tú dejarás esto. - Cariño...
...we got 4000 dollars' worth of doctor bills to pay.
...tenemos que pagar una factura del médico de 4000 dólares.
I will probably be making cheeseburgers for your grandkids.
Aún haré hamburguesas de queso para tus nietos.
Look at it. Your little ducktail over here.
Mírate. Pareces un patito.
Well...
Bueno...
...I wonder what my chances are, this morning...
...¿qué posibilidades tengo de hacer?...
...of interesting you kids in John Keats.
...que os interese John Keats?
None at all.
Ninguna.
Joe Bob?
¿Joe Bob?
I read that poem of his about the nightingale.
Leí ese poema suyo de un ruiseñor.
I didn't think it was so good.
Y no es tan bueno.
Sounded like he wanted to be a nightingale.
Parecía que quería ser un ruiseñor.
I don't think he wanted to be a nightingale, Joe Bob.
No creo que quisiera convertirse en ruiseñor.
Maybe he just wanted to be immortal.
Quizá solo quería ser inmortal.
All you have to do to be immortal is lead a good Christian life.
Para ser inmortal solo hay que ser un buen cristiano.
Anyone can do it if they love the Lord.
Podemos conseguirlo si amamos a Dios.
Well, maybe so, Joe Bob, maybe so.
Bueno, a lo mejor sí, Joe Bob.
Here now, let me-- Let me read you this.
Dejad que os lea esto:
"When old age shall this generation waste...
«Cuando la vejez llegue a esta generación...
...thou shalt remain in midst of other woe than ours...
...padeceré¡s males distintos a los nuestros!...
...a friend to man, to whom thou say'st:
...amigo del hombre, a quien dijiste:
'Beauty is truth, truth beauty'--
'La belleza es la verdad, la verdad, belleza'...
That is all ye know on earth...
...Eso es lo que en la Tierra sabéis...
...and all ye need to know."
...y no hace falta saber más».
Run, you little pissants, run!
¡Corred, capullos! ¡Corred!
Tough it out! Tough it out! You gotta be men like the rest of us.
¡Aguantad! Tenéis que ser hombres de verdad.
Ain't none of you pretty enough to be women.
No son guapos como una mujer.
Here, Joe Bob.
Venga, Joe Bob.
Quit flapping your arms. You look like a goddamn goose.
No agites los brazos. Pareces un ganso de mierda.
Even for a preacher's boy, you ought to be in better shape.
Debes de estar en forma.
What kind of female are you ever gonna get?
¿Qué chica querrá salir contigo?
Tough it out! Tough it out!
¡Aguantad!
Run, you little pissants.
Corred, capullos.
All right, off the court.
Muy bien, fuera de la pista.
If you all didn't jack off so damn much, maybe you could stay in shape.
Si no os hicierais pajas, quizá estaríais en forma.
Come here a minute, Sonny.
Ven un momento, Sonny.
Now, you do me a favour, and I'll do you one.
Si me haces un favor, yo te lo haré a ti.
Sure, coach.
Claro, entrenador.
My old lady's got to go to the doctor tomorrow.
Mi mujer tiene que ir mañana al médico.
You know women. Always something wrong.
A las mujeres siempre les duele algo.
Yeah, I guess.
Sí, supongo que sí.
Well, take it from me. Anyway, I haven't got have time to drive her.
Llévala tú. Yo no tengo tiempo de llevarla.
Now, if you'll do this for me, I'll get you out of civics class.
Si haces esto por mí, te ahorraré la clase de política.
I'll be glad to. That's the best offer I've had all day.
Bien. Es la mejor oferta que he tenido hoy.
You tell her you got to get back for practice...
Dile que tienes que volver...
...so she won't stay in there too long.
...que no se entretenga.
I've got enough bills to pay already.
No quiero que vaya de compras.
"Know what the trouble is with you?
«¿Sabes qué te sucede?
You ain't got no school spirit."
Que te falta espíritu deportivo».
Anarene High School, we love you
Anarene High School, te queremos
Love you ever so grand
Te queremos, siempre tan grande
We will always be so loyal
Siempre te seremos leales
Loyal to a man
Leales a un hombre
Anarene, defeat or victory
Anarene, derrota o victoria
We will always be true
Siempre te seremos fieles
Anarene High School, we love you
Anarene High School, te queremos
And we'll fight for you
Y lucharemos por ti
You need a haircut.
Necesitas un corte de pelo.
Hey, come on, Jimmie Sue. We're hungry over here too.
Venga, Jimmie Sue. Aquí tenemos hambre.
I'm coming. I'm coming. Hold your horses!
Ya voy. Paciencia.
Better watch it. Here comes your mama.
Cuidado, viene tu madre.
Jacy, we're having supper at home tonight.
Jacy, esta noche cenamos en casa.
I expect you there in 15 minutes, you hear?
Te espero allí en 15 minutos, ¿de acuerdo?
Okay, Mama. I was just giving the boys a ride.
Vale, mamá. Solo estaba paseando con los chicos.
Hey, Abilene.
Hola, Abilene.
Now here's a tune that's been on the pop hit list for some weeks.
Y ahora una canción que ha sido un éxito varias semanas.
Listen and tell us the name.
Escucha y dinos el título.
What is it?
¿Cuál es?
- "Shrimp Boats." - "Shrimp Boats" You got it!
- «Shrimp Boats». - ¡Lo ha acertado!
Very good, Thomas. You were in on that too.
Muy bien. Tú también participabas.
All right. There's $120. We're going along fine.
Aquí tienes 120 dólares. Ha ¡do bien!.
Now we come to City Limits. This is...
Ahora llegamos a City Limits. Esto es...
Guess you hate me tonight, huh?
¿Estás enfadada?
Oh, Mama, I love you, but I love Duane too. Even if you don't like it.
Mamá, te quiero, pero también a Duane. Aunque no te guste.
I don't care. I'd just hate to see you marry him, that's all.
No me importa. Pero no quiero que te cases con él.
You wouldn't be rich anymore.
Ya no tendrías dinero.
- I don't care about money. Not at all. - In two months, he'll stop flattering you.
- El dinero no me importa. - Te dejaría en dos meses.
You're pretty stupid then.
Entonces eres idiota.
You married Daddy when he was poor, and he got rich, didn't he?
Te casaste con papá siendo pobre y se hizo rico, ¿no?
Scared your daddy into getting rich, beautiful.
Lo asusté hasta que se hizo rico.
If Daddy could do it, Duane could too.
Si papá pudo, Duane puede.
Not married to you. You're not scary enough.
No casándose contigo. No asustas a nadie.
Well, you're rich and miserable. I sure don't wanna be like you.
Eres rica y desgraciada. No quiero ser así.
Not much danger of that.
No hay mucho peligro.
- You slept with him? - Mama!
- ¿Te acostaste con él? - ¡Mamá!
Go to the doctor sometime and arrange something...
Ve al médico y dile que te dé algo...
...so you don't have to worry about babies. You have to be careful.
...para que no te quedes embarazada. Tienes que tener cuidado.
But it's a sin unless you're married. You know I wouldn't do that.
Pero es pecado si no estás casado. Sabes que yo nunca lo haría.
Don't be so mealy-mouthed!
¡No seas hipócrita!
I thought if you slept with him...
Si te acostases con él...
...you might find out that there isn't anything magic about him.
...descubrirías que ese chico no es mágico.
Then we can send you away to a good school--
E irás a una buena escuela...
- But I don't wanna leave. - Marry some wealthy boy.
No quiero marcharme.
Why can't I stay here and go to college in Wichita Falls?
¿Por qué no puedo ir a la de Wichita Falls?
Because.
Porque no.
Everything is flat and empty here.
Aquí todo es aburrido y vacío.
And nothing to do!
Y no hay nada que hacer.
Can I have some of that?
¿Me das un poco?
Help yourself. Don't you have any?
Claro. ¿Tú no tienes?
Well, yeah, but I feel like smelling good right now.
Sí, pero me apetece oler bien ahora mismo.
Don't you ever feel like doing anything right now?
¿Nunca has tenido algún deseo repentino?
You ought to leave your face just like that.
No deberías maquillarte.
All you really need now is a little eyebrow pencil.
Lo único que necesitas es rímel.
Okay. Good night.
Vale. Buenas noches.
Just remember, beautiful, everything gets old if you do it often enough.
Recuerda, preciosa, que todo pierde encanto con la rutina.
So if you wanna find out about monotony real quick, marry Duane.
Si quieres descubrir pronto la monotonía, cásate con Duane.
- -Number one hit in the country right here on KTRN...
...el éxito número uno en el país ahora mismo aquí en K TRN...
...your Mutual station in Wichita Falls.
...tu estación en Wichita Falls.
Our old friend, Hank Williams, wrote that.
Nuestro viejo amigo, Hank Williams, escribió eso.
You're with us on Strike It Rich and the audience with a heart.
Siguen viendo Strike It Rich.
Say, if you like being with our audience, we're on television every day.
Si quieren venir como público, estamos en televisión cada día.
That's right. Every day, Monday through Friday, at 11:30 a.m. New York time.
Así es. Cada día. De lunes a viernes, a las 11:30 dela mañana.
Also, every morning, Monday through Friday, we're on radio.
Además, cada mañana, de lunes a viernes, estamos en la radio.
Look at your paper for time and station.
Busquen en su periódico la emisora.
And every Wednesday night at 9:00 right back here on television again.
Y cada miércoles por la noche a las 9:00 aquí en televisión.
The Colgate-Palmolive-Peet Company invite you to write us for tickets.
La compañía Colgate-Palmolive-Peet los invita a venir a vernos.
All you have to do is write to Strike It Rich...
Solo tienen que escribir a Strike It Rich...
...Box 500, Grand Central Annex...
...Apartado 500, Grand Central Annex...
Hello.
¿Diga?
- Abilene, you asleep? - No.
- Abilene, ¿dormías? - No.
Feel like company?
¿Quieres compañía?
Well, I thought I'd drive out, see how my well is coming.
Quería salir a ver cómo va el pozo.
Drill hard. You're better at oil wells anyway.
Dale duro. Eres mejor con el petróleo.
Before we continue, I'll remind you to look...
Antes de seguir, les recomiendo ver...
...for one of your favourite programmes. I know it's one of mine.
...uno de sus programas favoritos. Al menos, de los míos.
The whole family always watches The Colgate Comedy Hour.
La familia al completo ve The Colgate Comedy Hour.
Hello, Sonny. What you want?
Hola, Sonny. ¿Qué quieres?
Coach said you need a driver.
El entrenador me ha enviado.
Didn't he tell you I was coming?
¿No se lo ha dicho?
No, he didn't mention it. I thought he was gonna drive me himself.
No, no me ha dicho nada. Creía que me llevaría él.
I guess he just couldn't get off.
Supongo que no ha podido.
Let me just get the radio.
Voy a apagar la radio.
Is it something bad?
¿Es algo grave?
No.
No.
It's something very...
Es algo muy...
Thank you.
Gracias.
Here's the keys.
Aquí tiene las llaves.
I guess I'd better be getting back to school.
Tengo que volver al instituto.
It was nice of you to drive me.
Has sido muy amable.
Well, it beats sitting through civics, ma'am.
Es mejor que estar en clase de política.
Wouldn't you like to come in and have a soda?
¿No quieres entrar y tomarte una gaseosa?
If you can stand me for a few more minutes.
Si no te importa aguantarme.
Okay.
Vale.
I hate these northers.
Odio el viento del norte.
Would you prefer milk? Just sit at the table.
¿Prefieres leche? Siéntate a la mesa.
Or you can go right now if you want.
Si quieres puedes irte.
I was just scared to be alone for a minute. I'm sorry I made you come in.
Me daba miedo quedarme sola. Siento haberte hecho entrar.
I'll take a Dr Pepper.
Me tomaré un refresco.
You'll never forgive me, I know.
Nunca me perdonarás, lo sé.
Go on. You don't have to stay any longer.
Venga. No hace falta que te quedes más.
Thank you for the Dr Pepper.
Gracias por el refresco.
I guess you'll be glad when basketball season's over.
Se alegrará cuando se acabe el baloncesto.
Why?
¿Por qué?
Well, coach probably don't get to stay home much...
El entrenador no está mucho en casa...
...during football and basketball season.
...con lo del fútbol y el baloncesto.
My God, you don't know a thing about it, do you?
Dios mío, no tienes ni idea, ¿verdad?
You better go on to basketball practice.
Mejor vuelve al entrenamiento.
Thanks for the Dr Pepper.
Gracias por el refresco.
- Hi, Jacy. - Oh, hi.
- Hola, Jacy. - Hola.
Duane coming?
¿Va a venir Duane?
Say, you know Bobby Sheen, don't you? Over at Wichita Falls?
Conoces a Bobby Sheen, ¿verdad? De Wichita Falls.
I met him at the country club.
Lo conocí en el club de campo.
Well, he's gonna have this midnight swimming party tonight.
Hoy da una fiesta en su piscina a medianoche.
- You wanna run over there with me? - I can't.
- ¿Quieres venir conmigo? - No puedo.
I guess you heard about the last one.
Ya sabes lo que dicen.
His folks were gone to Miami, and everybody swam naked.
Sus viejos estaban en Miami, y se bañaron desnudos.
His folks are gone again, so it'll probably be pretty wild.
Sus viejos se han ido, así que será sonado.
Sure wish you could come. Bobby has great parties.
Ojalá vengas. Son unas fiestas estupendas.
A lot of kids from the club gonna be there.
Habrá más gente del club.
Gee, Lester, I'd like to go.
Vaya, Lester, me gustaría ir.
I'm gonna have a big problem with Duane though.
Pero voy a tener problemas con Duane.
Well, don't go off without me. Maybe I can.
No te vayas sin mí. A lo mejor sí puedo.
- Hi, Duane. - What did Lester want?
- Hola, Duane. - ¿Qué quería Lester?
Oh, Lester. He's such a bore.
Oh, Lester. Es un pelmazo.
- Hey, Abilene! - What do you say, buddy?
- ¡Eh, Abilene! - ¿Qué te cuentas?
Hey there. Hi.
Hola.
Merry Christmas.
Feliz Navidad.
This is Jackie Lee French. This is Lois Farrow, my boss's wife.
Esta es Jackie Lee French. Esta Lois Farrow, la mujer de mi jefe.
What do you mean, kissing her like that?
¿Cómo te atreves a besarla?
I ought to slap your face!
Debería pegarte.
Well, why don't you just kiss my ass?
¿Y por qué no me besas el culo?
I never come here to referee no fight.
No vengo de árbitro de boxeo.
Well, good, then come dance with me.
Bien, pues vamos a bailar.
Get yourself a drink, honey. I'll be back.
Tómate algo, cariño. Enseguida vuelvo.
Hi, Ruth.
Hola, Ruth.
Wait for me outside.
Espérame fuera.
--a thousand barrels of oil a day.
...mil barriles al día.
A thousand barrels.
Mil barriles.
It's too hot in here. Let's go outside.
Aquí hace mucho calor. Vámonos fuera.
I don't want drunks tromping on my feet.
No quiero tropezar con borrachos.
I got something to give you anyway.
Además tengo que darte algo.
- Hey, Sonny-
- Hola, Sonny.
Hi.
Hola.
Hi, Sonny.
Hola, Sonny.
Hi, Dad.
Hola, papá-
How you doing?
¿Cómo estás?
Okay.
Bien.
Well, that's good.
Me alegro.
See you.
Hasta luego.
Sure.
Claro.
- You mean, my Christmas present. - Yep.
- Mi regalo de Navidad. - Sí.
I haven't had time to get you anything yet.
No he tenido tiempo de comprarte nada.
I haven't had a minute to shop.
No pude ir de compras.
Hope you like it. I saved up for six months to get it.
He ahorrado seis meses para comprártelo.
Oh, it's just beautiful.
Es precioso.
It's just what I've been wanting.
Es justo lo que quería.
You're so sweet, spending all that money on me.
Eres un cielo, gastarte tanto dinero por mí.
Oh, you're so sexy, Duane.
Eres muy sexi, Duane.
I just wish I didn't have to leave you tonight.
Ojalá no tuviera que irme esta noche.
Well, you don't.
No hay porqué-
Oh, I do too. I could just kill my mother!
Tengo que hacerlo. Mataría a mi madre.
What do you mean?
¿Qué quieres decir?
She made me promise to go to a swim party in Wichita with Lester Marlow.
Me hizo prometer que iría a una fiesta en Wichita con Lester.
Because his folks are rich. Don't be mad.
Porque sus padres son ricos. Cálmate.
I ain't mad at you, but goddamn it!
Ya, pero vaya mierda.
It's all Lester's fault. He keeps asking Mama.
Es culpa de Lester. No hace más que pedírselo.
All I wanna do is stay with the man I love.
- Yo solo quiero quedarme con mi amor. - Maldición.
No, no, Duane! I gotta go. I gotta go.
¡No, Duane! Tengo que irme.
What do you mean, asking my girl for a date?
¿Cómo le pides una cita a mi chica?
- You turn me loose! - I will when you're ready to fight.
- ¡Suéltame! - Cuando pienses pelear.
Let's have it out!
¡Vamos, pelea!
Come on, Marlow.
Venga, Marlow.
Here, knock off that shit, boys. This is the Christmas season.
Dejad ya eso, chicos. Estamos en Navidad.
Run along here, Wichita.
Id a Wichita.
I can't stand here all night protecting your shoeshine.
No puedo pasarme toda la noche vigilándoos.
I just don't know what I'm gonna do about him. He's so crazy about me.
No sé qué hacer con él. Está loco por mí.
Nothing against Duane, but that's a roughneck for you.
No es nada contra Duane, pero un currante no te va.
They aren't sophisticated about these things.
No tiene clase.
Well, Merry Christmas!
Feliz Navidad.
Come on in, let's have some punch, boy.
Vamos dentro a beber ponche.
- Hi, Sonny. - Oh, hi.
- Hola, Sonny. - Hola.
- Wanna help me? - Okay.
- ¿Quieres ayudarme? - Vale.
You're not dancing. Don't you have a girlfriend?
No bailas. ¿Es que no tienes novia?
I did have. We broke up a couple months ago.
Tenía, pero rompimos hace dos meses.
Oh, why? Mind my asking?
Vaya. ¿Por qué? ¿Puedo preguntarlo?
I was going with Charlene Duggs.
Estaba saliendo con Charlene Duggs.
She thought I got fresh with her. I never did, really.
Dijo que me había propasado. Pero no lo hice.
I guess we broke up because we didn't like each other much to begin with.
Rompimos porque para empezar no nos gustábamos mucho.
I hope you're not sad about it.
Espero que no estés triste.
I don't think Charlene's near nice enough for you.
No creo que Charlene esté a tu altura.
I didn't see you dancing.
No la he visto bailar.
No, I don't dance much.
No, no me gusta.
Will you drive me to the clinic again next week?
¿Volverás a llevarme al médico la próxima semana?
Well, you bet.
Por supuesto.
We better not dawdle here.
Mejor no nos quedemos aquí.
Bobby.
Bobby.
Hey, look! New victims!
¡Eh, mirad! ¡Nuevas víctimas!
- Hi, Jacy.
- Hola, Jacy. - Hola.
Glad you could make it. We're dressed informally.
Qué bien que hayáis venido. Es una fiesta informal.
Hi, Jacy.
Hola, Jacy.
You know Annie-Annie.
Es Annie-Annie.
Wanna join the club?
¿Quieres entrar en el club?
Sure.
Claro.
Well, you gotta get undressed out there on the diving board.
Tienes que desnudarte encima del trampolín.
So everybody gets to watch.
Para que todos podamos verte.
We all do it the first time.
Todos lo han hecho.
- That's the rule. - Yeah. I did it last Easter.
- Es la regla. - Yo lo hice en Semana Santa.
- Okay? - Okay.
- ¿Vale? - Vale.
Everybody out for the strip show!
¡Todos a ver el striptease!
Don't pay any attention to Sandy. He's my little brother.
No hagas caso de Sandy. Es mi hermano.
If he gooses you or anything, I'll make him go to bed.
Si te molesta, lo mandaré a la cama.
Goodness! I hope I don't fall off this thing.
Espero no caerme.
Sandy can fish you out if you do.
Sandy te pescará si te caes.
Duane, been looking for you. Hey, where's Jacy?
Duane, te estaba buscando. ¿Y Jacy?
Oh, don't remind him. We just got him quiet. Want a drink?
No se lo recuerdes. Acaba de calmarse. ¿Un trago?
- Where'd you get it? - Found it in a guy's car.
- ¿Dónde estaba? - En un coche.
- When he weren't looking. - Let's do something.
- No me han visto. - Hagamos algo.
Good idea. Why don't we hunt up some pussy?
¿Por qué no nos vamos a buscar chicas?
Oh, you wouldn't know what to do with it if we found some.
No sabrías qué hacer si encontraras a una.
What happened?
¿Qué ha ocurrido?
Lester took his girl to a swimming party.
Lester se ha llevado a su chica a una fiesta.
Let's all go out and get a fuck.
Vamos a echar un polvo.
I know where's a heifer. It belongs to my Uncle Hank.
Sé dónde hay una vaquilla. Es de mi tío Hank.
Why the hell not?
¿Y Por qué no, joder?
- I say a heifer beats nothing. - Pussy's pussy!
- Es mejor que nada. - Un coño es un coño.
I don't want no heifer.
No quiero vaquillas.
We ought to buy Billy a piece of ass.
Hay que buscarle algo a Billy.
- Yeah, we oughtn't let him die a virgin. - Yeah.
- No podemos dejar que muera virgen. - Sí.
Mama says idiot kids don't live long.
Mamá dice que los imbéciles viven poco.
He ain't no idiot kid. He just don't talk.
No es imbécil, solo es mudo.
Bet he's still a virgin, though.
Seguro que es virgen.
Hey, we ought to fix him up with Jimmie Sue.
Tendríamos que montarle algo con Jimmie Sue.
It'd make no difference to Billy.
- A Billy no le importará. - No deberíamos hacerlo.
Why not? It wouldn't cost us more than $1.50.
¿Por qué no? No nos costaría más de un dólar 50.
If that's all, we ought to get her ourselves.
¿Solo eso? Deberíamos ir nosotros.
Shit! A heifer's better than Jimmie Sue.
Una vaquilla es mejor que Jimmie Sue.
Get the stupid little thing in here. I ain't got all night.
Meted a ese idiota. No tengo toda la noche.
Let's get those pants off, boys.
Venga, chicos, pantalones fuera.
You won't be a virgin much longer.
- No serás virgen mucho tiempo. - Hazte un hombre.
Grab on now. Come on, do your job.
A por ella. Haz lo que debes hacer.
Get her, Billy-boy!
A por ella, Billy.
This is the dumbest thing I ever seen!
¡Esto es estúpido!
- He don't even know what to do! - Come on, Billy. It worked for me.
- ¡Ni siquiera sabe qué hacer! - A mí me funcionó.
Damn it, put it to her, boy!
¡Maldición! ¡Métesela!
- Get her, Billy. - Come on, Billy. Screw it to her, boy.
- Métesela, Billy. - Dale. Hasta el fondo, tío.
You stop that yelling out there.
Parad de gritar ahí fuera.
It ain't even in!
Aún no la ha metido.
Goddamn!
¡Joder!
Goddamn, you stupid little thing!
Mierda, serás imbécil.
Couldn't even wait. Look at this mess!
Ni has podido esperar. Qué desastre.
You okay, Billy?
¿Estás bien, Billy?
You all right?
¿Estás bien?
Well, now I know. Idiots as bad as Mexicans.
Ahora lo sé. Un retrasado es peor que un chicano.
Don't bother me no more for that crazy thing.
No me molestéis más con esas tonterías.
Wouldn't mess with him again for less than three and a half.
No volvería a liarme con él por menos de tres y medio.
Which one of you bloodied his nose?
¿Quién le ha pegado?
I've told you all not to fight with Billy. He don't understand about fighting.
Os dije que no peleéis con Billy. No sabe qué es una pelea.
What happened, Sonny?
¿Qué ha pasado?
- It weren't none of us, Sam. - No, it was Jimmie Sue.
- No hemos sido nosotros. - Ha sido Jimmie Sue.
Jimmie Sue? How'd he get messed up with her?
¿Jimmie Sue? ¿Qué hacía con Billy?
We bought him a piece of ass. Thought he was tired of being a virgin.
Se la pagamos nosotros. Creíamos que no quería ser virgen.
She got mad about something and bloodied his nose.
Se ha enfadado por algo y le ha dado en la nariz.
You boys get on out of here.
Fuera de aquí, chicos.
I don't wanna have no more to do with you.
No quiero saber nada más de vosotros.
Scaring a poor, unfortunate creature like Billy...
Asustar a una pobre criatura como Billy...
...just so you could have a few laughs.
...solo para reíros un rato.
I've been around that trashy behaviour all my life.
He visto ese comportamiento asqueroso toda mi vida.
I'm getting tired of putting up with it.
Y me he cansado de aguantarlo.
You can stay out of this pool hall, my café...
Apartaos del billar, la cafetería...
...and my picture show too.
...y del cine.
I don't want no more of your business.
No quiero veros más.
We didn't mean for anything bad to happen, Sam. We--
No queríamos que pasara nada malo, Sam.
You didn't even have the decency to wash his face.
Ni siquiera le habéis lavado la cara.
We're his best customers. He can't run us off.
Somos sus mejores clientes. No nos puede echar.
Can he'?
¿Verdad que no?
Lucky I fell asleep. I'd hate not being able to shoot no pool.
Suerte que dormía. No me perdería una partida de billar.
You sure he won't come?
¿Seguro que no vendrá?
You know he won't. He's just starting basketball practice.
Claro que no. Ya ha empezado el entrenamiento.
It's all right.
Está bien.
I'm sorry I cried.
Siento haber llorado.
Just scared, I guess.
Supongo que estaba asustada.
He ain't gonna come.
No va a venir.
They're probably running plays right now, I bet.
Estarán dando vueltas a la pista.
No, not scared of that.
No es eso.
Scared I could never do this, I guess.
Supongo que tenía miedo de no poder hacerlo.
Can't seem to do anything without crying about it.
Parece que no puedo hacer nada sin llorar.
How could you like me?
¿Cómo puedo gustarte?
I like you.
Me gustas mucho.
I'm glad.
Me alegro.
Come on in. I ain't gonna throw bottles at you.
Pasa. No voy a tirarte botellas a la cabeza.
Hi.
Hola.
What have you been doing? You lost weight.
¿Dónde has estado? Has adelgazado.
Ain't had any of your cheeseburgers in weeks.
Hace semanas que no como tus hamburguesas.
Come on. I'll fix you one.
Venga, te prepararé una.
Even though that wasn't a very nice thing y'all done to Billy.
Aunque lo que le hicisteis a Billy no está bien.
Can't blame Sam.
No puedes culpar a Sam.
- Was that your idea? - No.
- ¿Fue idea tuya? - No.
Duane's? He was there, wasn't he?
¿De Duane? Estaba allí, ¿no?
Just didn't have the decency to own up to it.
No tuvo la decencia de confesarlo.
Don't worry, I won't tell on him. I should, though.
No te preocupes, no diré nada. Aunque debería.
Sure smells good.
Huele de maravilla.
One thing I know for sure.
Puedes estar seguro de algo.
A person can't sneeze in this town...
Aquí no estornudas sin que te ofrezcan un pañuelo.
- What you mean? - Nothing.
- ¿Qué quieres decir? - Nada.
It's an awful small town for any kind of carrying on.
En un pueblo tan pequeño se sabe todo.
Don't forget to put some onions on.
No te olvides de la cebolla.
And some people got a lot of guns.
Y algunos tienen muchas armas.
All right, you don't need my advice anyway.
Pero no necesitas mis consejos.
Why don't you go play a record? These will be done in a minute.
¿Por qué no pones un disco? Estará lista enseguida.
Just come in to say hello to Genevieve.
Solo he venido a saludar a Genevieve.
Sonny...
Sonny...
...food's getting cold.
La comida se enfría.
What are you grinning about?
¿Por qué me miras así?
Chicken-fry me a steak, and try to use meat this time.
Hazme un filete. Y esta vez usa carne.
I heard about the ball game last night.
Me han contado lo del partido de ayer.
121 to 14.
Ciento veintiuno a 14.
Must be pretty near a record.
Debe de ser casi un récord.
Sam.
Sam.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
I reckon y'all need glasses.
Supongo que necesitáis gafas.
Now hold still.
Espera.
Want some more cookies?
¿Quieres más galletas?
- More milk? - I'm full.
- ¿Más leche? - Estoy lleno.
How come you've stayed with the coach?
¿Cómo es que sigues con el entrenador?
You don't like him much.
No te gustaba.
I wasn't brought up to leave a husband.
No me educaron para dejar a mi marido.
I guess that's why.
Supongo que por eso.
Maybe I was just scared to.
A lo mejor me da miedo.
I never noticed how ugly this room is.
No me había fijado en lo feo que es este cuarto.
What's your favourite colour?
¿Qué color te gusta más?
I don't know. Blue.
No lo sé. El azul.
- Maybe I'll re-paper it. - Why'd you marry him?
- Quizá lo empapele. - ¿Por qué os casasteis?
I don't know.
Qué se yo.
My mother didn't like him. Maybe that was it.
A mi madre no le gustaba. A lo mejor por eso.
But I was 20 years old.
Tenía 20 años.
I thought hairy-chested football coaches were about it.
Creía que los entrenadores de pelo en pecho eran lo mejor.
I'm gonna buy us a new quilt.
Voy a comprar una manta nueva.
A blue one.
Azul.
What you think he'd do if he found us?
¿Qué haría si nos descubriera?
Shoot us, probably.
Probablemente nos mataría.
He's always glad to have an excuse to use his deer rifle.
Le encanta tener una excusa para sacar su rifle.
I thought you boys wanted to fish.
Creía que queríais pescar.
Come on. Keep an eye on them corks, Billy.
Vamos. Vigila los corchos, Billy.
I don't think there's anything in this tank except turtles.
En este pantano no hay más que tortugas.
That's what I like about it, tell you the truth.
Por eso me gusta, para serte sincero.
- Wanna try one? - Sure.
- ¿Quieres uno? - Claro.
I never liked to clean fish or eat them either.
No me gusta limpiar pescado ni comerlo.
You spend half your time picking out bone.
Te pasas todo el tiempo sacando espinas.
I just come out here to get a little scenery.
Solo vengo aquí por el paisaje.
Too pretty a day to spend in town.
Un día muy bonito para estar en el pueblo.
You wouldn't believe how this country's changed.
No creerías cómo ha cambiado esta tierra.
First time I seen it, there wasn't a mesquite tree on it.
La primera vez que la vi no había ni una chumbera.
Or a prickly pear neither.
Ni un higo chumbo.
I used to own this land, you know.
Esta tierra era mía, ¿sabes?
First time I watered a horse at this tank...
La primera vez que bebió mi caballo aquí...
...was more than 40 years ago.
...fue hace más de 40 años.
I reckon the reason I always drag you out here is...
Supongo que te traigo hasta aquí...
...I'm just as sentimental as the next feller when it comes to old times.
...porque me pongo sentimental recordando los viejos tiempos.
Old times.
Los viejos tiempos.
I brought a young lady swimming out here once...
Solía traer aquí a una jovencita a nadar...
...more than 20 years ago.
...hace más de 20 años.
It was after my wife had lost her mind.
Fue después de que mi mujer perdiera el juicio.
And my boys was dead.
Mis hijos habían muerto.
Me and this young lady was pretty wild, lguess.
Supongo que esa chica y yo estábamos bastante locos.
In pretty deep.
Y muy enamorados.
We used to come here on horseback and swim without no bathing suits.
Veníamos aquí a caballo y nadábamos desnudos.
One day, she wanted to swim the horses across this tank.
Un día quiso cruzar nadando a caballo al otro lado.
Kind of a crazy thing to do, but we done it anyway.
Era una locura, pero lo hicimos.
She bet me a silver dollar she could beat me across.
Se apostó un dólar de plata a que me ganaba.
She did.
Y me ganó.
This old horse I was riding didn't wanna take the water.
Mi viejo caballo no quiso meterse en el agua.
But she was always looking for something to do like that.
Siempre estaba buscando cosas para hacer como aquella.
Something wild.
Algo salvaje.
I'll bet she's still got that silver dollar.
Supongo que aún tendrá ese dólar de plata.
Whatever happened to her?
¿Qué fue de ella?
Oh, she growed up.
Se hizo mayor.
She was just a girl then, really.
Entonces no era más que una niña.
Here, let me help you with that.
Deja que te ayude.
Why didn't you ever marry her after your wife died?
¿Por qué no os casasteis cuando murió tu mujer?
She was already married.
Ya estaba casada.
Her and her husband was young and miserable with one another...
Ella y su marido eran jóvenes y desgraciados...
...like so many young married folks are.
...igual que muchas parejas jóvenes.
I thought they'd change with some age...
Pensé que cambiarían con los años...
...but it didn't turn out that way.
...pero no ha sido así.
- Is being married always so miserable? - No. Not really.
- ¿Estar casado es así de miserable? - No siempre.
About 80 percent of the time, I guess.
Solo un 80 por ciento del tiempo.
We ought to go to a real fishing tank next year.
El año que viene iremos a un pantano de verdad.
It don't do to think about things like that too much.
Pensar tanto en el pasado no sirve de nada.
If she was here, I'd probably be just as crazy now...
Si ella estuviera aquí, volvería a enloquecer...
...as I was then in about five minutes.
...igual que antes, en menos de cinco minutos.
Ain't that ridiculous?
¿No es ridículo?
No, it ain't really.
No, lo cierto es que no.
Being crazy about a woman like her is always the right thing to do.
Siempre está bien enloquecer por una mujer como ella.
Being a decrepit, old bag of bones, that's what's ridiculous.
Ser un saco de huesos decrépito, eso sí que es ridículo.
Getting old.
Hacerse viejo.
My God, I'm glad I wasn't on fire.
Dios, suerte que no estoy ardiendo.
I would've burned to death before you got one button undone.
Podría carbonizarme antes de soltar un botón.
I'm going to get a drink of water.
Voy a beber agua.
Hi.
Hola.
I wondered where you went. Annie-Annie asleep?
No sabía dónde estabas. ¿Duerme Annie-Annie?
Yeah.
Sí.
Nice. You a virgin?
Me gustas. ¿Eres virgen?
Guess I am.
Supongo que sí.
Too bad.
Qué pena.
- I don't wanna be, though. - I don't blame you.
- Pero no quiero serlo. - No te culpo.
Come see me when you're not.
Avísame cuando no lo seas.
Why don't we just go someplace? I'm sick and tired of this town.
Vamos a otro sitio. Estoy harto de este pueblo.
- You're the only friend I got. - You mean, go and stay gone?
- Eres mi único amigo. - ¿Irnos y no volver?
No, I don't know.
No, no sé.
Hey, we go to Mexico. Be back sometime Monday.
Vamos a México. volveremos el lunes.
- You reckon the pickup would make it? - Yeah. How much money you got?
- ¿La camioneta aguantará? - Sí. ¿Tienes dinero?
Oh, 30 bucks about.
Unos 30 pavos.
Well, I got 40. We can make it. Come on!
Vale, yo tengo 40. Podemos. ¡Venga!
Okay.
Vale.
You boys want--? Hey.
Chicos, ¿queréis...?
- Where are you going? - Mexico.
- ¿Adónde vais? - A México.
Where?
¿Adónde?
Better come with us, Sam. We're headed for the valley.
Vente con nosotros, Sam. Vamos hacia el valle.
- Going where did you say? - Mexico.
- ¿Adónde? - A México.
- It's about the wildest. - All the way down.
- Es una locura. - Allá vamos.
You going all the way to Mexico tonight in this old heap of junk?
¿Os vais hasta México de noche en esta chatarra?
My God.
¡Joder!
Reckon the town will get along without us till Monday?
¿Podréis pasar sin nosotros hasta el lunes?
I reckon.
Creo que sí.
If I was young enough to bounce, I'd probably go with you.
Si fuera más joven, iría con vosotros.
- Need any money? - No, we got plenty.
- ¿Necesitáis dinero? - No, tenemos.
Well, you'd better take some for some insurance.
Bueno, mejor llevaos algo más por si acaso.
Take money below that border, it sort of melts sometimes.
El dinero se deshace más allá de la frontera.
Thanks, Sam.
Gracias, Sam.
Try not to drink too much of that buggy water.
No bebáis mucha de esa agua infecta.
We'll just drink beer and tequila.
Solo beberemos cerveza y tequila.
You catch the clap, you'll wish you hadn't drunk nothing.
Como pilléis la gonorrea, estáis listos.
Oh, Well.
Bueno.
We'll see you.
Ya nos veremos.
So long!
¡Hasta la vista!
Duane. Hey, wake up!
Duane. ¡Eh, despierta!
We're back.
Ya hemos llegado.
My stomach don't feel so good. Got any more of those Tums?
Me duele el estómago. ¿Te quedan pastillas?
You ate them all before we got to San Antone.
Te las acabaste antes de llegar a San Antonio.
Genevieve will have something. My stomach don't feel so good.
Genevieve tendrá algo. Me duele mucho.
"Closed."
Cerrado.
Closed?
¿Cerrado?
Yeah.
Sí.
I ain't never seen her closed before.
Nunca lo había visto cerrado.
No, not even for Christmas.
No, ni siquiera en Navidad.
Maybe Sam will have something. I'm sick.
A lo mejor Sam tiene algo. Estoy mareado.
Well, it ain't that early.
Pero si no es tan temprano.
Must be some kind of holiday.
Debe de ser festivo.
Sam don't close on holidays.
Sam no cierra los festivos.
Maybe he had to go someplace.
Habrá tenido que ir a algún sitio.
Well, let's go ask Andy.
Vamos a preguntarle a Andy.
Okay.
Vale.
- Hey, Andy. Hey, where is everybody? - Somebody will steal the town.
- Oye, Andy. ¿Dónde están todos? - Alguien robará el pueblo.
Asleep. Everybody that's got any sense.
Durmiendo. Los listos.
Why'd Sam close the café?
¿Por qué ha cerrado Sam?
Oh, yeah. Y'all been gone, ain't you?
No estabais aquí, ¿verdad?
Gone to Mexico.
Estabais en México.
- You don't know about it. - About what?
- No lo sabéis. - ¿El qué?
Sam died yesterday morning.
Sam murió ayer.
Died?
¿Ha muerto?
Yep. Quite a blow.
De repente.
Keeled over one of the snooker tables. Had a stroke.
Cayó encima de la mesa de billar, un derrame cerebral.
- Sam the Lion? - Yep.
- ¿Sam, el León? - Sí.
Sam's dead.
Sam ha muerto.
He was quite a feller.
Era un buen tipo.
He had his own way of doing things, that's for sure.
Hacía las cosas a su manera, no cabe duda.
They found his will. Craziest thing you ever heard.
Han encontrado su testamento. Menuda locura.
He left you the pool hall, Sonny. What do you think about that?
Te ha dejado el billar, Sonny. ¿Qué te parece?
He left Genevieve the cafe.
Dejó la cafetería a Genevieve.
That's the only thing he done that made any sense.
Eso es lo único que ha hecho bien.
Left the picture show to old Miss Mosey.
Y el cine, a la vieja señorita Mosey.
Hell, she's too far gone to even run a popcorn machine.
Y no sabe ni cómo va la máquina de las palomitas.
And the craziest thing of all...
Lo más desquiciado es...
...he left $1000 to Joe Bob Blanton, the preacher's boy.
...que le ha dejado mil pavos a Joe Bob, el hijo del reverendo.
Beats all I ever heard of.
Es lo más increíble.
He could just as easily left that to me.
Me los podría haber dejado a mí.
I deserve it at least as much as that ignorant little bastard.
Me lo merezco tanto como ese capullo ignorante.
Anyhow, it's done.
De todos modos, ya está hecho.
They're burying him tomorrow.
Mañana será el entierro.
Come in.
Adelante.
- I love you. - I love you too.
- Te quiero. - Yo también.
Oh, Duane, hurry.
Duane, date prisa.
What's wrong, honey?
¿Qué sucede, cariño?
I don't know.
Qué se yo.
That tickles. You know I can't stand to be tickled.
Me haces cosquillas. No lo soporto.
What's the matter? Aren't you gonna do it?
¿Qué pasa? ¿No piensas hacerlo?
I don't know what's wrong.
No sé qué me ocurre.
How could anything be wrong? Just go on and do it.
No digas tonterías. Venga, empieza.
Oh, what's the matter with you?
¿Pero qué te sucede?
I don't know. Something's happened.
No lo sé. Ha sucedido algo.
Well, get off a minute! You might fall and mash me.
¡Aparta! Me estás aplastando.
I don't know what happened.
No lo entiendo.
It was Mexico. No telling what you got down there.
A saber qué habrás pillado en México.
I just hate you! I don't know why I ever went with you.
¡Te odio! No sé por qué salgo contigo.
I don't know what happened.
No lo entiendo.
Put your clothes on. You think I wanna sit around here and look at you naked?
Ponte la ropa. ¿Crees me gusta verte ahí desnudo?
I knew you couldn't do it. Now I'll never not be a virgin!
Sabía que no podrías hacerlo. ¡Nunca dejaré de ser virgen!
What do we tell everybody? The whole class knows.
¿Y qué decimos? Lo saben todos.
I just wanna cry. You're the meanest boy I ever saw.
Quiero llorar. Eres lo peor que he visto.
My mother was dead-right about you.
Mi madre tenía toda la razón.
I don't know what happened.
No lo entiendo.
Don't go out there! We haven't had time to do it. They'd know.
¡No salgas! No hemos tenido tiempo de hacerlo.
I don't want one soul to know. You better not tell one soul.
No quiero que lo sepa nadie. No lo digas.
You just pretend it was wonderful!
Di que ha sido fantástico.
Well, I'm sorry. I don't know what happened.
Lo siento. No sé qué ha sucedido.
If you say that one more time, I'll bite you!
Si vuelves a decir eso, ¡te mato!
Tell us about it, Jacy. What was it like?
Cuéntanoslo, Jacy. ¿Cómo ha sido?
I just can't describe it.
No puedo explicarlo.
I just can't describe it in words.
No puedo explicarlo con palabras.
Jacy.Jacy.
Jacy.Jacy.
I can do it now. I know I can.
Ya puedo hacerlo. Sé que puedo.
JacY.
JaCY-
Oh, quit prissing! I don't think you did it right anyway.
¡Deja de presumir! No ha sido para tanto.
Come on.
Ven.
It's your graduation present. Hope you like it.
Es tu regalo de graduación. Espero que te guste.
I never seen one as nice.
Es la más bonita que he visto.
- Hello. - Jacy?
- Hola. -  ¿Jacy?
What's on your feeble mind, Duane?
¿Y ahora qué quieres?
Same as it's been. I want a date.
Lo de siempre. Una cita.
Why don't you just go back to Mexico?
¿Y por qué no vuelves a México?
I guess girls are just easier to please down there.
Allí las chicas son fáciles de contentar.
Just go with me one more time.
Sal conmigo solo una vez más.
You can at least see me.
Solo para vernos.
Find somebody else to pester. Got a new boyfriend.
Ve a fastidiar a otra. Tengo otro novio.
- And I can't be talking to you. - Who?
- No puedo hablar contigo. - ¿Quién es?
- Bobby Sheen, of course. - Bobby Sheen?
Bobby Sheen, claro.
- You crazy? - I certainly am not.
- ¿Estás loca? - Pues no.
I guess I wanted to go with him all along and never realised it.
Siempre quise salir con él, pero no me daba cuenta.
Maybe we'll see you in Wichita sometime.
Ya nos veremos por Wichita.
Goddamn it! Goddamn it to hell!
¡Maldita sea, joder!
I hate to see you go, Duane.
No quiero que te vayas.
Not a goddamn thing to stay for.
No hay nada por lo que quedarse.
Roughnecks say you can get a job out in Odessa anytime.
Los petroleros dicen que hay trabajo en Odessa.
Come on back if you don't.
Vuelve si no lo encuentras.
Hey, listen, you hear they busted up, let me know.
Oye, si oyes que han roto, dímelo.
Why don't we watch the movie?
¿Por qué no vemos la película?
Hi. Didn't hear you.
Hola. No te he oído.
Gene home?
¿Está Gene?
No, he and Mama went to the club.
No, ha ¡do al club con mamá!.
What are you doing home on a Saturday night?
¿Te quedas en casa un sábado?
Bobby Sheen ran off and got married.
Bobbie Sheen se fugó y se ha casado.
Annie-Annie Martin.
Con Annie-Annie Martin.
Want me to turn the TV off?
¿Apago la tele?
No, I'm gonna go play some pool. Tell your dad that well came in okay.
No, voy al billar. Dile a tu padre que el pozo va bien.
I wish I could go to the pool hall. I've always wanted to.
Ojalá pudiera ir. Siempre he querido verlo.
It's terrible, the things girls aren't allowed to do.
No sé por qué no pueden entrar las mujeres.
Well, hell, come on. I'll show you the pool hall.
Pues venga, vamos. Te enseñaré el billar.
Aren't there people there?
¿No habrá nadie?
If there are, they'll be in back asleep now.
Si había alguien, ya se habrá ¡do a dormir!.
Won't bother us. Got my own key.
No nos molestarán. Tengo una llave.
Okay, I will then.
Muy bien, vamos.
Goodness, it sure is dark in here.
Esto está muy oscuro.
What a night! I never thought something like this would happen.
¡Qué noche! Nunca pensé que ocurriría algo así.
How about hopping out?
¿No piensas bajar?
And in Chicago today, Governor Adlai E. Stevenson accepted...
Y hoy en Chicago, el gobernador Adlai E. Stevenson aceptó...
...the Democratic presidential nomination...
...la nominación del partido demócrata...
...and picked Senator John Sparkman of Alabama to be his running mate.
...y eligió al senador John Sparkman de Alabama para acompañarlo.
In Dallas county, General Dwight D. Eisenhower scored...
En Dallas, el general Dwight D. Eisenhower consiguió...
...a second landslide victory over old-guard Republican forces.
...su segunda victoria sobre la vieja guardia republicana.
Oh, he's just awful, Mama! Why do you fool with him?
¡Es horrible, mamá! ¿Cómo puede gustarte?
- Daddy's nicer than him, isn't he? - He sure is, beautiful.
- Papá es mucho mejor, ¿no? - Claro que sí.
Your daddy's a very nice man.
Tu padre es muy agradable.
I ought to been giving Abilene hell instead of him.
Debería pelearme con Abilene y no con él.
Bobby was the last one. I'm just gonna be an old maid.
Bobby fue el último. Voy a ser una solterona.
That's just the way it goes sometimes. You win a few, you lose a few.
Así son las cosas. A veces ganas y a veces pierdes.
What do you do?
¿Qué voy a hacer?
Nothing's ever the way it's supposed to be.
Nada es nunca como debería.
You're right. Come on.
Tienes razón. Vamos.
I want to tell you, what I've done has not worked out too well.
Lo que yo he hecho no me ha salido muy bien.
I think maybe we better think of something else for you.
Pensaremos en algo diferente para ti.
Right now, I guess Ruth Popper's got about as good a setup as anyone.
Al final Ruth Popper ha sido la más lista.
Why, sure. Sonny's reasonably good-looking and he's young.
Pues claro. Sonny es bastante guapo y es joven.
Don't you know about that? It's been going on about six months now.
¿No lo sabes? Hace ya más de seis meses.
- I thought you kids knew everything. - That's silly!
- Creí que lo sabíais todo. - ¡Tonterías!
She's 40 years old.
Tiene 40 años.
So am I, honey. It's kind of an itchy age.
Yo también, cielo. Es una edad complicada.
Want an orange?
¿Quieres una naranja?
I don't believe it.
No me lo puedo creer.
Sonny's always wanted to go with me.
Siempre le he gustado yo.
Pretty easy shot, sheriff.
Una tirada fácil, sheriff.
Sheriff, we got some trouble.
Problemas.
Goddamn you, Monroe! You made me scratch.
¡Ala mierda, Monroe! Me has despistado.
Sorry, sheriff, but Johnny Clarg's little girl's kind of been kidnapped.
Lo siento, pero han raptado a la pequeña de Johnny Clarg.
They say the preacher's boy put her in his car two hours ago.
El hijo del pastor la metió en su coche.
Well, what the hell? Maybe Joe Bob just give her a ride home.
¿Pero qué narices? Joe Bob querría llevarla a casa.
Be doing her a favour in this hot weather.
Le haría un favor con este calor.
Who'd want to kidnap Molly Clarg?
¿Quién querría raptar a Molly Clarg?
I just know she's not home.
Pues no está en casa.
They was seen headed out of town toward Olney.
Los han visto en dirección a Olney.
Well, Mrs Clarg's kind of afraid that Joe Bob might be...
La señora Clarg teme que Joe Bob vaya a...
- ...gonna molest her or something. - Sonny.
- ...propasarse con ella o algo así. - Sonny.
You and some of these boys come with us.
Tú, ven con algún otro chico.
If that's the way it is, no telling what we'll find.
Si es así, no quiero saber qué nos encontraremos.
Molly! Molly!
¡Molly!
Get him! Ain't you going to?
¡Deténganlo! ¿A qué esperan?
Here's my little girl.
Mi pequeña.
He's the one that done it. Why don't you get him?
Lo ha hecho él. ¿Por qué no lo detienen?
If my husband was here, he'd kill him dead.
Si estuviese mi marido, ya lo habría matado.
What did you do to that child? We know you done something.
¿Qué le has hecho? Sabemos que le has hecho algo.
Come on.
Ven.
Filthy!
¡Cerdo!
Here now, grab her. None of this goddamn frenzy.
Cuidado, cogedla. Ya basta de locuras.
It's the Lord's justice, son.
Es la justicia divina.
You'll suffer with the murderer and the thief.
Sufrirás con los asesinos y ladrones.
Sonny, drive that Plymouth to town. We gotta get this man to jail.
Sonny, llévalo al pueblo. Hay que meterlo en la cárcel.
- Doctor said he didn't do nothing. - Never had the guts.
- El doctor dice que no la tocó. - No se atreve.
- Preacher's boy. - Sheriff figured he done something.
- El chico del pastor. - El sheriff cree que sí.
Yeah.
Sí.
Isn't it terrible, Sonny? Were you there? Did you see anything?
¿No es horrible, Sonny? ¿Estabas allí? ¿Tú viste algo?
Oh, weren't nothing to see except Mrs Clarg.
No vi nada. Solo a la señora Clarg.
If she had a gun, she might've killed us all.
Si tuviera una pistola, nos habría matado a todos.
Joe Bob didn't do nothing.
Joe Bob es inocente.
He must've done something. It scares me to death.
Algo habrá hecho. Me da un miedo de muerte.
You just never can tell when something terrible's gonna happen.
Nunca sabes cuándo va a suceder algo horrible.
It's okay. They got him now.
Calma. Ya lo han detenido.
I called you before.
Te he llamado antes.
You did?
¿Ah sí?
I felt lonesome.
Me sentía sola.
Thought you might wanna drive around awhile.
Pensé que querrías dar una vuelta.
Well, I'm supposed to be someplace.
Me están esperando.
I'm still a little scared. Please take me riding.
Estoy un poco asustada. Por favor, llévame a algún sitio.
Well, where will we drive?
¿Adónde vamos?
You ever hear from Duane?
¿Qué hay de Duane?
Got a postcard.
Recibí una postal.
I really feel sad about that.
Eso me pone muy triste.
He's-- He's making 320 a month. Said he bought a car.
Gana 320 al mes. Tiene un coche.
I guess I'll always be a little bit in love with Duane.
Siempre amaré un poco a Duane. Lo teníamos todo en contra.
It wasn't easy being the one to break up.
No fue fácil ser la que rompió.
- Sonny. - What?
I ' ¿Qué?
Not here.
Aquí no.
I'm too old for screwing in cars.
Ya soy mayor para follar en un coche.
I don't like to hurry.
No me gusta ir deprisa.
Why don't we go to Wichita and get a motel room?
¿Por qué no vamos a un motel en Wichita?
I'm afraid to. I think my folks are watching me.
Me da miedo. Mis padres me vigilan.
They know I don't wanna go to college.
Saben que no quiero estudiar.
They might think we're gonna run off and get married.
Creerían que vamos a huir y casarnos.
We'll do it when it's safe.
Ya lo haremos cuando sea seguro.
We got all summer.
Tenemos todo el verano.
- Hey, Duane. - Hey, buddy!
- Eh, Duane. - ¡Eh, tío!
You turned roughneck.
¿Ya trabajas?
Gotta make a living so I can keep the pool hall open.
Necesito pasta para mantener el billar.
When'd you get in?
¿Cuándo llegaste?
About 2. I thought I'd surprise you.
A las dos. Quería darte una sorpresa.
Is this yours?
¿Es tuyo?
Yeah, how about that? Thirty-eight thousand miles, and she runs like new.
¿Qué te parece? 60 mil kilómetros y tira como nuevo.
- Say, you want a beer? - Not me.
- ¿Una cerveza? - Yo no.
That's about all I eat for breakfast anymore.
Eso es mi único desayuno.
Hey, sure is a nice car.
Sí que es un coche bonito.
Yeah, I like to drive it so much, I thought I'd just drop home for the weekend.
Me gusta tanto conducir que he venido el fin de semana.
Yeah, you can't take too good care of a car like this.
Nunca se cuida demasiado un coche como este.
I wash her every week.
Lo lavo cada semana.
Oh, it looks great.
Está fantástico.
Hear about Joe Bob?
¿Sabes lo de Joe Bob?
Yeah, I always knew he was crazy.
Sí, siempre supe que estaba loco.
He didn't do nothing, except get her to take her underpants off.
No le hizo nada, solo que se quitara las bragas.
- He's out of jail now. - Yeah.
Ya ha salido de la cárcel.
Are you still screwing that old lady?
¿Aún te tiras a esa vieja?
No. Yeah. I've been kind of busy.
No. Sí. He estado ocupado.
I seen old Leroy last week.
La semana pasada vi a Leroy.
He said he thought you and Jacy had been going together.
Me dijo que Jacy y tú salís juntos.
Yeah, we have, a little.
Sí, bueno, un poco.
She's been kind of bored, so once in a while, we go eat Mexican food.
Se aburre, así que a veces comemos en un mexicano.
Well, I hear that ain't all you been eating.
Oí que eso no es todo lo que hacéis.
Well, whoever told you that don't know what he's talking about.
El que te lo haya dicho no sabe de qué habla.
Sure, I've been going with her. Why not?
Hemos salido. ¿Por qué no?
I never said I blamed you for it. I don't blame you much.
Yo no te lo he echado en cara.
I never thought you'd do that. I thought we were best friends.
No creí que lo hicieras. ¿No éramos amigos?
We are. What you so mad for? I never done nothing.
Lo somos. ¿Por qué te enfadas? No he hecho nada.
- Screwing my girl ain't nothing? - I ain't screwing her.
- Tirarte a mi chica. - No lo he hecho.
- Hell, you ain't! - Well, I ain't.
- ¡Cómo que no! - Pues no.
- She's not your girl. - She is my girl!
- Y no es tu chica. - ¡Lo es!
You don't even live here anymore.
Tú ya no vives aquí.
That don't make no difference! I'm getting her back.
Eso no importa. La pienso recuperar.
She's gonna marry me one of these days.
Un día se casará conmigo.
- She won't. - We're meant to get married.
- No. - Somos el matrimonio ideal.
She's off to college soon.
Irá a la universidad.
I doubt I'll ever get to go with her again myself, once she gets off.
Dudo que siga saliendo conmigo cuando se marche.
I never saw what it could hurt to go with her this summer though.
No veo qué pasa por salir con ella este verano.
- She's never gonna marry you. - She is! Don't tell me she won't!
- Nunca se casará contigo. - ¡Sí! ¡Cállate!
She'd never let you screw her. That's for sure.
Nunca se acostaría contigo. Eso seguro.
Hell, I was just seeing how honest you was.
Solo quería ver si eras honesto.
Jacy would never let you screw her. You ain't that good a cocksman.
Jacy nunca lo hará contigo. No eres bastante.
You never even screwed Charlene Duggs all that time.
Ni siquiera te tiraste a Charlene Duggs.
Course I didn't!
¡Claro que no!
You know why?
¿Y sabes por qué?
Because you had the pickup all the time Saturday night, that's why.
Porque tú tenías la camioneta todos los sábados.
Nobody could've screwed in the time I had.
Nadie podía hacerlo.
I could've screwed her in five minutes. I wouldn't need no pickup.
Yo me la habría tirado hasta sin camioneta.
She only went with you because you was in the backfield and I was in the line.
Solo salía contigo porque estabas en el equipo y yo no jugaba.
What you talking about? We was in love.
¿Qué dices? Nos amábamos.
Oh, you was. She likes me just as much as she ever liked you.
Tú sí. Yo le gusto más de lo que le gustabas tú.
- That's a lie. - I'll stay with her all night too.
- Es mentira. - Y dormiremos juntos.
- She promised. - You won't either.
- Lo prometió. - No lo harás.
I Will. Why Shouldn't I?
¿Y por qué no?
She done told me you couldn't even do it that time in Wichita Falls.
Me ha dicho que aquella vez no pudiste hacerlo.
What happened?
¿Qué ha ocurrido?
Sonny?
¿Sonny?
This is your turntable matinee here on KTRN...
Este es su programa matutino aquí en KTRN...
...where you can hear Fulton Lewis, Jr every Monday through Friday at 6 p.m.
...donde escucha a Fulton Lewis, Jr. de lunes a viernes a las seis de la tarde.
Now here's Hank Williams.
Ahora Hank Williams.
There's a lady in the waiting room. She sent you this.
Hay una mujer ahí fuera. Te envía esto.
Could you tell her I'm asleep?
Dígale que estoy dormido.
Please?
Por favor.
All right.
Está bien.
That too cold?
¿Está fría?
No, it's great.
No, está bien.
Say, I hear Duane joined the Army.
Me han dicho que Duane se ha alistado.
Good place for him too.
Un buen sitio para él.
He didn't mean to hit me with the bottle.
No quería darme con la botella.
That boy's always had meanness in him.
Ese chico siempre tuvo algo malvado.
Jacy's just the kind of girl that brings out the meanness in a man.
Jacy es una chica que saca lo peor de un hombre.
She's just like her grandmother.
Es igual que su abuela.
I hadn't ought to talk about them. We was all good friends once.
No debería hablar de ellos. Antes éramos buenos amigos.
Dan roughnecked with Gene Farrow.
Dan trabajaba con Gene Farrow.
He and Lois used to live in this one-room place...
Él y Lois vivían en un estudio...
...over the newspaper office.
...encima del periódico.
Lois couldn't afford a flour sack, much less a mink.
Lois no tenía ni para harina y menos para un visón.
I've always had a soft spot for her, though.
Sin embargo, ella siempre me ha caído bien.
Yeah, I wondered a lot of times what would've happened...
Me pregunto muchas veces qué habría pasado...
...if my Dan had made the strikes that Gene made.
...si mi Dan hubiese hecho como Gene.
They offered that rig to him first.
Le ofrecieron el pozo primero a él.
YUP-
Sí.
Dan Morgan never took a chance in his life.
Dan Morgan no era de los que se arriesgan.
Do you wish y'all had made it?
¿Te habría gustado?
Sure, I wish we'd made it.
Claro que me habría gustado.
I guess the Army won't take me now, I just got one good eye.
Creo que el Ejército no me aceptará con un solo ojo.
You wanna go over to Korea and get yourself killed?
¿Quieres ir a Corea a que te maten?
You ain't got your senses back yet, what few you ever had.
Aún no has recuperado la razón, la poca que has tenido siempre.
The café won't run itself. You rest up now.
La cafetería no va sola. Descansa.
Here's for the cheeseburger.
Cóbrame la hamburguesa.
Okay, I'll bring your change when I bring your supper.
Vale, te daré el cambio cuando te traiga la cena.
Thanks.
Gracias.
Sonny?
¿Sonny?
Oh, come on in.
Ah, pasa.
"I Can't Help It." Hank Williams. Big sound from last year.
«I Can't Help It». Hank Williams. Gran canción del año pasado.
Now here's a brand-new one, just came in from Webb Pierce.
Y ahora aquí tenemos una nueva de Webb Pierce.
Gonna hear it a lot, I bet.
Seguro que la van a escuchar mucho.
Oh, I was so worried. I just had to see you.
Estaba preocupada. Debía verte.
Oh, I've been missing you.
Te he echado de menos.
And I'm a lot better than I was. Here, sit down.
Ya estoy mucho mejor. Ven, Siéntate.
You can't believe how famous we are. We're all anybody talks about in town.
No sabes qué famosos somos. Todos hablan de nosotros.
- Yeah, I guess so. - I want us to get married.
- Supongo que sí. - Casémonos.
- What? - I really do.
- ¿Qué? - De verdad.
Get married?
¿Casarnos?
Just as soon as you want to. Don't you want to?
Cuando tú quieras. ¿No quieres?
Oh, yeah.
Sí.
I bet the town will be knocked for a loop. They'll never forget it.
El pueblo se quedará de piedra. Nunca lo olvidarán.
Ain't you going to college?
¿Y la universidad?
I don't care about that. I love you, and that's more important.
No me importa. Te quiero, y eso es más importante.
You were so dear to fight for me.
Te has peleado por mí.
My folks won't like it, but we'll run off.
Tendremos que fugarnos.
- They'll kill us. - No, they won't.
- Nos matarán. - No lo harán.
- They'll kill me. - They'll get over it.
- A mí sí. - Lo superarán.
You're working for Daddy now anyway.
Y ahora trabajas para papá.
Pretty soon, they'll love you just as much as I do.
Muy pronto te querrán tanto como yo.
Can we?
¿Lo haremos?
Sure, I just hope I can see to drive.
Claro, espero poder conducir.
Don't you worry. I can drive.
No te preocupes. Ya conduciré yo.
Don't do that, Sonny.
No hagas eso, Sonny.
Why not?
¿Por qué no?
We're man and wife now. We can do anything.
Somos esposos. Podemos hacerlo todo.
Not while I'm driving. I might have a wreck.
No si conduzco. Podría tener un accidente.
Goodness. Wouldn't it be awful if Mama and Daddy got the police after us?
Sería horrible que mamá y papá nos enviaran a la Policía.
- They don't even know where we are. - Well, I had to leave them a note.
- No saben dónde estamos. - Tuve que dejar una nota.
So they wouldn't be worried out of their mind.
Así no se preocuparán mucho.
Oh, you shouldn't have done that.
No debías haberlo hecho.
I figured they'd have to know sometime.
Algún día tendrán que saberlo.
Well, what could they get us for?
Bueno, ¿y qué pueden hacernos?
We got a right to get married. Ain't we?
Tenemos derecho a casarnos. ¿O no?
I guess so.
Supongo que sí.
I wish you didn't have that stupid eye patch. It's really creepy.
Ojalá no llevaras ese estúpido parche. Es horrible.
Oh, hey, I can take it off pretty soon.
Pronto me lo podré quitar.
About two hours, will be Lake Texoma. Have a room to ourself.
En dos horas estaremos en el lago Texoma y tendremos una habitación.
My goodness! You're sitting so close, I can barely drive.
Dios mío, estás tan cerca que no me dejas conducir.
Oh, goodness.
¡Vaya, hombre!
Howdy.
Hola.
- What part of Texas y'all from? - Anarene.
- Hola. ¿De dónde sois? - De Anarene.
Newlyweds, ain't you?
Recién casados, ¿verdad?
Y'all better follow me on in. I think somebody's looking for you.
Será mejor que me sigáis. Os están buscando.
We got a right to get married. How can you arrest us?
Podemos casarnos. ¿Por qué nos detiene?
I ain't arresting you. I just want you to come with me.
No os he detenido. Solo quiero que me sigáis.
I don't know what your rights are.
No sé qué queréis.
I guess we better follow him, honey.
Será mejor que lo sigamos.
I'll just be heartbroken if my folks have done this.
Qué vergüenza si han sido mis padres.
You think I worked hard so my daughter could end up in a pool hall?
¿Crees que voy a dejar a mi hija en un billar?
- We was gonna get another apartment. - I'll bet!
- Íbamos a buscar un piso. - No me digas.
Where are your car keys?
¿Y las llaves?
It's a hell of a note! Just a hell of a note!
¡Vaya mierda de nota!
- Oh, shut up and take her home. - You bet I will!
- Calla y Ilévatela. - Claro que lo haré.
You take her car. As far as I'm concerned, he can walk!
Coge su coche. Por mí, él puede volver a pie.
- Not much of a wedding night, huh? - Nope.
- No es la mejor noche de bodas, ¿eh? - No.
Not much of one.
No es la mejor.
Here. Have a little drink of bourbon. It'll pick you up.
Toma. Bebe un poco de whisky. Te animará.
Take all of it. I'm gonna drive.
Acábatelo. Yo debo conducir.
You won't believe this...
No me creerás...
...but you're lucky we got you clear of her quick as we did.
...pero suerte de que os separemos tan rápido.
You'd have been a lot better off staying with Ruth Popper.
Habría sido mejor quedarte con Ruth Popper.
Does everybody know about that?
¿Lo sabe todo el mundo?
Course.
Claro.
Sounded like a good deal to me, kiddo. Shouldn't let Jacy turn your head.
A mí me parecía un buen negocio. No deberías haberte fijado en Jacy.
Well, she's prettier.
Bueno, es más guapa.
I guess I shouldn't have, though. I guess I treated her terrible.
Pero reconozco que hice mal. La he tratado muy mal.
Guess you did.
Creo que sí.
Sure weren't out of Texas very long.
No nos hemos alejado de Texas.
Well, Oklahoma's not much of an improvement.
Oklahoma no es mucho mejor.
It's not the same now.
Ahora ya no es lo mismo.
Nothing's really been right since Sam the Lion died.
Nada ha ido bien desde que Sam, el León, murió.
No.
No.
No, it hasn't.
No, todo ha cambiado.
Oh, God.
Dios mío.
I get sad if I think of Sam for long.
Me pongo triste si pienso en Sam.
Did you know he had beautiful hands?
Tenía las manos muy bonitas.
I guess you liked him, didn't you?
Supongo que le gustaba, ¿verdad?
I guess everybody did.
A todo el mundo le gustaba.
Well, I'll tell you, it was different with me, Sonny.
Deja que te diga que conmigo era distinto.
I loved him.
Yo lo amaba.
He loved me too.
Yél a ml.
Are you--?
¿Usted es?...
Are you the one he'd take swimming...
¿Usted es la que iba con él?...
...out at the tank?
...al pantano?
He told you about that, huh?
¿Así que te lo contó?
Yeah, I was the one.
Sí, era yo.
I guess if it wasn't for Sam, I'd...
Supongo que de no ser por Sam...
...just about have missed it. Whatever it is.
...me lo habría perdido. Sea lo que sea.
I'd have been one of them amity types that thinks that...
Habría sido una de esas amigables que piensan...
...playing bridge is about the best thing that life has to offer.
...que jugar a las cartas es lo mejor que ofrece la vida.
Old Sam the Lion.
Sam, el León.
Sam the Lion. Nobody knows where he got that name. I gave it to him.
Nadie sabe de dónde sacó ese nombre. Se lo puse yo.
One night...
Una noche...
...it just came to me.
...se me ocurrió.
He was so pleased.
Él estaba encantado.
I was 22 years old then.
Yo solo tenía 22 años.
Can you imagine?
¿Te lo imaginas?
I tell you, Sonny...
Te lo digo, Sonny.
...it's terrible to only meet one man in your whole life...
Es horrible conocer un solo hombre en tu vida que sabe lo que vales.
Just terrible.
Es horrible.
I've looked too.
Y he buscado.
You wouldn't believe how I've looked.
No sabes cómo he buscado.
- Well, now I know why Sam liked you. - Loved me.
- Ahora ya sé por qué le gustaba a Sam. - Me quería.
Loved you, I mean.
La quería, claro.
Do you?
¿Lo sabes?
I can kind of see what he saw in you too.
Creo que yo también veo lo que vio en ti.
Nope. I'll just go on home.
No. Me voy a casa.
Go on. Get out.
Venga, baja.
Think I could--? Think I could learn to drink?
¿Cree que aprenderé a beber?
You might. Better keep on practising.
A lo mejor. Pero sigue practicando.
That Logan boy's a quarterback, now, ain't he?
Ese Logan es quarterback, ¿no?
Boy, we've finally got us a team!
¡Hombre! Por fin tenemos equipo.
Didn't back in your day, did they, Sonny?
No como en tus tiempos, ¿eh?
No, we wasn't much good.
No, no éramos buenos.
Well, you just never learned the fundamentals.
Nunca aprendisteis lo básico.
You know, blocking and tackling.
Ya sabes, bloquear y placar.
Not like this team.
No como este equipo.
- When was it you graduated? - Last year.
- ¿Cuándo te graduaste? - El año pasado.
You don't mean it.
¿En serio?
Seems like longer than that since you and old Duane played ball.
Parece más lejos cuando tú y Duane jugabais.
I seen Duane a while ago.
He visto a Duane antes.
He's home on leave, wearing his uniform.
Está de permiso, de uniforme.
I ain't seen him yet.
Yo aún no lo he visto.
- How are you, Chester? - Fine, coach.
- ¿Qué tal, Chester? - Bien.
Now, listen, see if we can't stretch that goddamn thing a little.
A ver si puedes estirar un poco esa cosa.
You know a man never ought to cheat, unless it's for a good cause.
Un hombre no debe hacer trampas si no es por una buena causa.
He's a good old boy, ain't he?
Es un buen hombre, ¿verdad?
Hi, Mrs Jackson.
Hola, señora Jackson.
Duane here?
¿Está Duane?
That's his car out there, ain't it? He's here if he ain't walked off.
Ese es su coche, ¿no? No creo que se haya ido a pie.
Hi, how you been?
Hola, ¿qué tal te va?
Oh, pretty ggm
Bastante bien.
I been thinking all week that I'd run into you.
Toda la semana he creído que te vería.
Yeah.
Sí.
I heard you was going off to Korea.
He oído que te vas a Corea.
Thought I'd get over here and see you before you got off.
He pensado pasar antes de que te vayas.
Glad you did. I'm taking the bus out early in the morning.
Me alegro. Me voy mañana con el primer autobús.
Want to go to the picture show?
¿Quieres ir al cine?
Miss Mosey's having to close it. Tonight's the last night.
La señorita Mosey lo cierra. Hoy es la última noche.
Yeah, might as well go.
Sí, podemos ir.
Hate to miss the last night. Take the Mercury.
No quiero perdérmela. Vamos en el coche.
Be the last chance I'll have to drive it for a while.
No voy a conducirlo en mucho tiempo.
Ready, Matthew?
¿Preparado, Matthew?
All ready.
Preparado.
Take them to Missouri, Matt.
Llévalos a Missouri, Matt.
- That was a good movie. - Yeah.
- Buena película. - Sí.
Seen it here before once.
Ya la había visto.
Why don't we run over to Wichita and drink some beer?
¿Vamos a beber unas cervezas a Wichita?
Okay. I got lots of time till morning.
Vale. Tengo mucho tiempo hasta mañana.
Sure.
Claro.
Well, so long, Miss Mosey.
Adiós, señorita Mosey.
Sorry you're closing the show.
Siento que cierre.
Nobody wants to come to shows no more.
La gente ya no quiere venir al cine.
Kid baseball in the summer, television all the time.
Béisbol en verano, y televisión todo el año.
Sam had lived, I believe we could've kept it going.
Si Sam viviera, no habríamos tenido que cerrar.
But I just didn't have the know-how.
Pero yo no sé cómo hacerlo.
Won't be much to do in town with the picture show closed.
No habrá mucho que hacer en el pueblo sin el cine.
Well, so long.
Bueno, adiós.
Duane.
Duane.
You watch out now, overseas.
Ten cuidado en aquellas tierras.
Sure weren't no women around.
Donde estaba no había mujeres.
I guess the next piece of ass I get will be yellow.
El próximo culo que vea será amarillo.
I wish I was going with you.
Ojalá me fuera contigo.
Why don't you take care of the car for me?
¿Por qué no cuidas del coche?
Your ma don't need it?
¿Y tu madre?
I wouldn't want her driving it. No better than she can drive.
No quiero que lo conduzca. Conduce muy mal.
Help her take the groceries home if you got time.
Llévala a comprar alguna vez.
Okay.
Vale.
You ever--?
¿Has...?
You ever hear from Jacy?
¿Sabes algo de Jacy?
No, not a thing.
No, no sé nada.
She don't get home much. Ain't been back to town since August.
No viene mucho a casa. La última vez fue en agosto.
I guess she just stays in Dallas all the time.
Creo que se queda en Dallas.
Yeah, probably does.
Sí, seguramente.
I guess there's lots to do down in Dallas.
Habrá mucho que hacer ahí.
I ain't over her yet, you know.
Aún no la he olvidado, ¿sabes?
I ain't over her yet.
Aún no la he olvidado.
It's the damnedest thing.
Eso es lo más jodido.
That's the only reason--
Ese es el único motivo...
The only reason you and I got into it that time, you know.
Ese es el único motivo por el que nos peleamos aquella vez.
Hey, reckon she likes it down in Dallas?
¿Le gustará Dallas?
It's hard to say. Maybe she does.
Difícil saberlo. Quizá.
Reckon you and her would've got it all straighted out if I hadn't butted in?
¿Crees que lo habrías arreglado si yo no me hubiese metido?
No.
No.
No, they'd have annulled me too, even if we had.
No, aun así, también me habría anulado.
Y'all--?
¿Vosotros...?
Y'all never even got into the motel?
¿No llegasteis a ir al motel?
No.
No.
Well...
Bueno...
...better get on before we both freeze.
Vamos antes de quedarnos congelados.
Here are the keys.
Toma las llaves.
- So long, buddy. - So long, Duane.
Adiós, colega.
Be careful.
Ten cuidado.
I'll take care of the Mercury.
Te cuidaré el coche.
I'll see you in a year or two if I don't get shot.
Hasta dentro de dos años si no me matan.
He ought to be in bed.
Debería estar durmiendo.
- The wind is blowing real hard. - He was right out in front of that station.
- El viento soplaba fuerte. - Estaba justo enfrente de la estación.
Christ, the trucker didn't have a chance.
Dios, el conductor no pudo evitarlo.
Yeah, he's out here all the time doing something.
Siempre estaba aquí fuera haciendo algo.
I can see it wasn't your fault.
No fue su culpa.
The sand was blowing. I never noticed him.
Había arena. No lo he visto.
Figured nobody'd be in the street.
Creí que no había nadie.
What was he doing out there carrying that broom?
¿Qué hacía aquí fuera?
He weren't doing nothing. Just a simple-minded kid.
No estaba haciendo nada. Era un retrasado.
- Never had no sense. - Wasn't your fault.
- No era listo. - No es culpa suya.
Hell, no, mister! I can see that.
¡Claro que no! Eso ya lo sé.
He was just a dumb old kid.
Solo era un chico tonto.
Didn't know enough to keep his ass out of the cold.
No sabía ni resguardarse del frío.
Let's go to the café. Ain't had breakfast.
Vamos a tomar un café.
I'd still like to know what he was doing with that broom.
Me gustaría saber qué hacía con esa escoba.
He was sweeping, you sons of bitches!
Estaba barriendo, hijos de puta.
He was sweeping!
Estaba barriendo.
Y'all got some crazy kids in this town, if you ask me.
En este pueblo tenéis chicos muy raros.
Hi.
Hola.
Could I have a cup of coffee with you?
¿Puedo tomar una taza de café contigo?
I guess.
Bueno.
I'm sorry. I'm still in my bathrobe.
Perdona. Estoy sin arreglar.
What am I doing apologising to you?
¿Por qué te pido perdón?
Why am I always apologising to you, you little bastard?
¿Por qué siempre te pido perdón? ¡Cabrón!
Three months I've apologised to you without you even being here!
Hace tres meses que te pido perdón aunque no estés aquí.
I haven't done anything wrong. Why can't I quit apologising?
No hice nada mal. ¿Por qué no dejo de pedir perdón?
You ought to be sorry!
¡Tú deberías pedirlo!
I wouldn't still be in my bathrobe if not for you.
No iría en pijama si no fuese por ti. Ya me habría arreglado.
You're the one made me quit caring if I got dressed or not!
Tú tienes la culpa de que no me importe vestirme.
Just because your friend got killed...
Porque ha muerto tu amigo...
...you want me to forget what you did and make it all right.
...quieres que olvide lo que me has hecho.
I'm not sorry for you.
Pues no me das ninguna pena.
You'd have left Billy too, just like you left me.
Dejaste a Billy como me dejaste a mí.
I bet you left him plenty of nights...
Lo dejarías solo muchas noches...
...whenever Jacy whistled.
...en cuanto Jacy te silbaba.
I wouldn't treat a dog that way.
No trataría así a un perro.
You thought I was so old and ugly, you didn't owe me any explanation.
Pensaste que era tan vieja y fea que no merecía una explicación.
You didn't need to be careful of me.
No debías cuidar de mí.
There was nothing I could do about you and her, so why be careful?
No podía hacer nada. ¿Por qué preocuparse?
You didn't love me.
No me querías.
Look at me.
Mírame.
Can't you even look at me?
¿Ni siquiera puedes mirarme?
See?
¿Lo ves?
Shouldn't have come here.
No debías haber venido.
I'm around that corner now.
Ahora estoy muy lejos.
You've ruined it.
Lo echaste a perder.
It's lost completely.
Está todo perdido.
Just your needing me won't make it come back.
No volverá solo porque ahora me necesites.
Never you mind, honey.
No te preocupes, cariño.
Never you mind.
No te preocupes.